(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T08:49:51.406837",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ワン、ツー、スリー！ワン、ツー、スリー！
One, two, three! One, two, three!
おはようございます！
Good morning!
おはよう、船長！
Good morning, Senchou!
な、何してんの？何してんの？
Wh-What are you doing?
え？ちょっと自分用にね、来たんですけど。
Hm? I came here for myself, but...
船長は何をしていたんですか？
what was Senchou doing?
いや、祭りはちょっとね、やっぱアイドルタルのダンスの練習を欠かしちゃいけないなと思ったから、ダンスの練習ちょっとしてたよ。
Well, I thought we shouldn't skip idol dance practice, so I was practicing a bit.
じゃ、船長、そういうことで、
Then Senchou, in that case...
待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
え、船長も一緒に練習しよ！え、船長踊れないの？
Hey, Senchou, let's practice together! Wait, can't Senchou dance?
踊れますよ！
I can dance!
踊れる？
You can?
え？何しての？何？ダンス？え、40歳？
Huh? What are you doing? What? Dancing? Huh, 40 years old?
やめろ！
Stop it!
あ、でも、確かに、やっぱ3Dお披露目のときとかも、ね？
Ah, but true, when we revealed our 3D models and stuff, you know?
色々やったけど、なんかちょっとね、やっぱり動きが、っていうのはちょっと言われてたから。
We did various things, but people said stuff like, "Your movements are a bit..." so...
なるほどね。
I see.
で、これがさ、やっぱさ、あれなんじゃないの？こういう感じのやつ。これ？
And this, you know, isn't it like this? This kind of thing? This?
気象予報みたいな。
Like a weather forecast.
ま、それは置いといて、船長はね、ちょっとまあ、確かに動きが微妙だって言うのはね、ちょいちょい言われてますから。
Well, putting that aside, Senchou, people have been pointing out that your movements are a bit subtle, so...
そうですね。ちょっと船長もダンス練習しようかなあ。
That's right. Maybe Senchou should practice dancing too.
あ、なるほど。え、どれくらいなの、実力？なんかアイドルステップみたいなのはできるんですか？
Oh, I see. Um, how good are you? Can you do things like idol steps?
あ、できますよ。
Ah, I can.
うん、じゃあちょっとやってみよう。
Yeah, then let's try it out.
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー！ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー！
One, two, three, four! One, two, three, four!
えーと、あのスケートでリレーしてるんですかね？
Um, are you doing a relay on skates or something?
え、スケートレース？スケートレース？もう一回！やばいやばい！
Eh, skate race? Skate race? Once more! Oh no, oh no!
ちょ、アイドルステップっていうのはこういうやつね。こう言うやつね。
Wait, an idol step is like this. This kind of thing.
あ、そうそう。じゃあ一緒にやろうよ。可愛く踊れる？
Ah, right, right. Then let's do it together. Can you dance cute?
どっこいしょみたいなのね。どっこいしょっていうのは40歳。
Like "dokkoisho" or something. Saying "dokkoisho" is for 40-year-olds.
やめてください！さて、悪い、悪い印象を与えて...
Please stop! Now, to give a bad, bad impression...
船長に可愛い印象を与えるために、可愛いアイドルステップをまず1回目練習しよう。
to give Senchou a cute impression, let's practice a cute idol step first.
まず、右、ぎ、右、左、左！
First, right, left, right, left!
ちょっとね、歩幅広いと思うよ。肩幅くらい。
Also, I think your stride is wide. About shoulder-width.
あ、そう。で、早いから、タン、うん、タン。
Ah, right. And since it's fast, tan, tan.
やめる？もう今日は。何すんの！
Giving up? For today? What are you doing!
じゃあこれからね、やる事がなくなっちゃいますよ。
Then you'll have nothing to do from now on.
もうっかい、もうっかい、ちょっともう一回ね。行くよ。
Once more, once more, let's do it again. Here we go.
タン、タン。違う、ん？まだ1歩も引けてない。
Tan, tan. No, hmm? You haven't taken a single step back yet.
そうそうそう。あともね、まず1、2、
That's right, that's right. Also, first 1, 2,
まず1、2。そうそう！
first 1, 2. Exactly!
タン、うん、タン、タン、うん、タン！リハビリしとるんか。楽しい！
Tan, tan, tan, tan! Are you doing rehabilitation? Fun!
ダンスっすね、ダンスって。これよ！これよ！
Dancing is fun, huh? This! This!
これをちょっと跳ねさせると、こうなる。
If you bounce this a bit, it becomes like this.
イエーイ！チョメリグ！
Yay! Chomerigu!
なんて？なんかね、こんな、こんな、こんななんだよ、船長。
What? It's like, so, so, so like this, Senchou.
それはやりすぎじゃん。
That's going too far.
そこまでのダンスじゃないし。
It's not that level of dance.
いや、これ大丈夫かな？今日ダンスを教えようと思ったんだけど。
Wait a minute, is this okay? I thought I'd teach you dancing today, but...
いや、分かった分かった。無理しなくていいよ、おばさん。
I got it, I got it. You don't have to push yourself, old lady.
やめて！うるさい！ちょっと待て、逆レジェ、ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅ！ごめんごめんごめん！
Stop it! Shut up! Wait a minute, reverse leg...
そうだね。じゃあ、ちょっと今日は曲も踏まえてさ、練習しようよ。
That's right. Then, today let's practice considering the song too.
ちょっとちょっとちょっと待って、私何もしてないんだけど。
Wait, wait, wait a minute, I haven't done anything.
走ってない！走ってない！こんな走ったうちに入らないよ。
I didn't run! I didn't run! This doesn't count as running.
じゃあ今日は、船長に1曲くらいさ、覚えて帰ってよ。
So today, Senchou, memorize at least one song before you go back.
おお！いや、1曲とは言わないよ。古はさ、難しいでしょ、多分。
Oh! Well, I won't say a whole song. Furua is difficult, probably.
なにそれバカにしてるんですか？覚えられる自信は...
What is that, are you making fun of me? Confidence to remember...
っきりってある？
Is there a fixed time?
時間が足りないからね。
Because we don't have enough time.
1番だけって
Just the first part...
時間が、1時間しか
We only have one hour,
ないのだからね。じゃあ1番だけきょうは。
so let's just do the first part today.
おん。
Yeah.
あの、ごめんね。
Um, sorry.
何が可笑しいの、お前。
What's so funny, seriously?
きっく？
Kick?
1番の...キック、キック、キック、ライダーキックしよう。
Let's do a Rider Kick for the first part.
わかったわかった。落ち着いて。落ち着いて。
Got it, got it. Calm down.
1番だけ、1番だけ今日やりましょう。
Let's just do the first chorus today.
じゃあ早速なんだけど、祭りのことをまず
So right away, first about Matsuri's...
大丈夫？ちょっと汗拭いといたほうが良くない？
Are you okay? Wipe your sweat a bit.
1番だけ祭りのダンスを見よう見まねで踊ってよ。
Just copy and dance Matsuri's dance.
アイ...任せて。コピーには自信があります。
I... leave it to me. I'm confident.
本当？自信ある？
Really? You're confident?
じゃあできるね。じゃあちょっとここ
Then you can do it. Let's see...
ライダキック？うん。
Rider Kick? Yeah.
はしゃいでんね。
You're getting hyper.
バカさをね、今全部に出してる。
You're showing all your goofiness.
じゃあちょっと、あの、移動しますか？
So um, shall we move?
ここだとあれなんでね、アイドルな感じのところに。
Somewhere with more of an idol vibe.
じゃあせーのでジャンプして移動しますよ。
We'll jump on three and move.
行きまーす。せーの！
Let's go. Ready, go!
やったー！やったー！できたー！
Yay! Yay! We did it!
それでは早速、1番ね。
So right away, the first chorus, right?
とりあえず1番だけ。ちょっと、ちょっと待って、ちょっと。
Just the first chorus for now. Wait a sec.
ちょっと疲れちゃった。
I got a bit tired.
体力なさすぎしょんなの。
My stamina is way too low.
はい、大丈夫。
Yeah, I'm fine.
本当は大丈夫？
Are you really okay?
まだ何もしてないよ。
We haven't done anything yet.
いや、だってさ、ライダーキックとかしたじゃん。
Well, we did the Rider Kick and stuff.
え？それは
Huh? That's...
私じゃないからわかんないよ、ライダーキックは。
It wasn't me, so I don't know about that.
ライダーキック！やめて、やめて、待って待って。
Rider Kick! Stop, stop, wait, wait.
こんなんじゃ疲れないよ。
You won't get tired from something like this.
よし、やりましょう。
Alright, let's do this.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
じゃあ、早速、じゃあ、曲はね、今日やるのは
So the song we're doing today is...
スイートマジックって曲知ってます？
Do you know "Sweet Magic"?
いいじゃないすか！
That's great!
可愛らしいじゃないですか。
Isn't it super cute?
もしかしてフォホワイトでも近いということで可愛らしい。
It's close to White Day, so it's cute.
スイーティンね。
Sweetin', right?
そうスイーティンな感じで踊っていきましょう。
Let's dance with that sweet feeling.
まず1番のみでございます。
First, just the first part only.
いいですか？
Is that alright?
くらいはね余裕で流しちゃっても大丈夫でしょうか？
Can we breeze through that easily?
いいですよ。船長は、松井シャンプーの真似していただければいいでしょ。
Captain, just mimic Matsuri's dance.
見ながら踊ってください。
Just dance while watching.
コピーには自信がありますよ。パンダマシーンと呼ばれるこの女。
I'm confident. The Panda Machine.
それでは早速参りましょう。ミュージック、スタート！
Let's get right into it. Music, start!
え？
Huh?
ちょっと待って
Wait a second.
難しい。
It's hard.
あ、いいよ。
Ah, good.
難しい。
It's hard.
待って、知らないじゃん！
Wait, I don't know this!
できてる、できてる！
We're doing it, we're doing it!
頑張ってるな、あ、合ってるよ。
You're trying hard, ah, that's right.
あ、待って、こうか。
Ah, wait, like this.
またそれか！
That again!
そう、おんなじ、おんなじ。
Yeah, the same, the same.
あ、近いな、これ。
Ah, this is close.
違う、違う、違う。
No, no, no.
い、頑張って！
Hang in there!
さすがに...
Naturally...
ここまで！
That's it!
先輩、疲れちゃった。
Senpai, I'm exhausted.
先輩？
Senpai?
何してんの？
What are you doing?
見よう見まねで。
Just copying.
あ、これ決めポーズ、最後の決めポーズ。
Ah, this is the final pose.
それ？
That?
そうですね。あの、ぜえぜえ言ってるけど大丈夫ですか？
You're panting, are you okay?
あ、大丈夫、全然。
Ah, I'm totally fine.
本当？
Really?
これ演技なんで。
This is acting.
ばあちゃんも大丈夫、ばあちゃんも。
Granny is fine too, Granny is.
疲れた演技してるだけ。
Just acting tired.
演技しなくていいよ、全然。
You don't need to act, really.
疲れたほかに、もう疲れるな。
I'm getting even more tired.
え、どうだった？今の踊ってみて、もういける？
How was it dancing? Can you do it now?
いけるって思った。
I thought we could.
思わないけど、無理だろ！
I didn't think so at all, no way!
待てよ！1から順番に説明してくれます？
Wait! Can you explain it in order?
じゃあまず、じゃあちょっとここは、今さっきのはビフォアとして撮っておきましょう。
Let's keep the previous one as a 'before' video.
踊れなかったころの先輩ね。
The senpai who couldn't dance.
はいはい。そしてアフターでまたここのステージに戻ってきて踊ろう、先輩。
Let's come back here and dance, senpai.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
じゃあ一ターン、えっと、いつものね、事務所に戻ろう、ホロライブのキララジャンプね。
Let's return to the office with a Kirara Jump.
じゃあきららジャンプで戻る練習をしましょう。せーの！
Let's practice the Kirara Jump. Ready, go!
はーい！
Okay!
あれ？
Huh?
もう一回きますか。せーの！はーい！
Shall we try again? Ready, go!
おっけーおっけーおっけー。戻ってきました。
Okay, okay, okay. We're back.
戻ってきましたよ！
We're back, you know!
じゃあ早速いきましょう！
Then let's get right into it!
まずね、この「Sweet Magic」って曲は、
First, this song "Sweet Magic"
パッパッパラッパッパッパラッパッパラッパッパラッパッパッていうのが...
has this pa-pa-para-pa-pa-para... part.
はい。
Right.
そこは、大体...でもそれがでてきたら全部同じなんですけど
That part is... once it comes up, it's all the same, but
うん。
Yeah.
まずこう手を...
First, hands like this...
こっち？
This way?
そうそうそう、でちょっと平らぎ過ぎてから、ここをちょっと閉じて、あ、そうそうそう！
Yeah, and after flattening a bit too much, close it here... Ah, yes, yes, yes!
可愛くね？
Isn't it cute?
そうそう、可愛い可愛い！
Yeah, yeah, super cute!
そしたら、あの右足を、後ろにこう...重心をやる感じで、
Then, put your right foot back... shifting your weight like this,
タッ、うん、タッ、うん、タッ、うん、タッ、え？
ta, yeah, ta, yeah, ta, yeah, ta, eh?
えとね、え？
Um, let's see, eh?
ちょっと、もうちょっとねこっちの足が前で、
Wait, a bit more... with this foot in front,
それで、えっと後ろに、うん、ターンってやってみて。
and then, uh, go back, yeah, try turning.
こう？えと、あ、
Like this? Uh, ah,
1回足上げて、後ろにこうやって
raise your foot once and do this backward.
交代させるみたいな。こうやってこうでしょ？こうやって。こういうこと？
Like switching places. Like this, right? Is that what you mean?
諦めんなよ！
Don't give up!
あ、せっかくならもっと...右足を...タッてできる。
Ah, if we're going for it, more... right foot... you can go ta.
右足、こっち？そうそうそうそう。
Right foot, this way? Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
で、そのままポンってやる。こうこと？あ、そんで、そのときに左足は上げる。こう？
And just do pon. Like this? Ah, and lift your left foot at that time. Like this?
そうそうそう、やだみっちゃんやだ。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, Mitty, no.
それを、ターン、ターン、ターン、ターンって、あーま、それでいいよ。
Do that: turn, turn, turn, turn... ah well, that's fine.
こう？うん、まあ妥協。
Like this? Yeah, well, compromise.
うん、これね？次わ...
Yeah, this? Next is...
それがパッパッパラッパッパッパラッパッパラッパッパッて
That's pa-pa-para-pa-pa-para-pa-para...
待って待って待って、軸はもっともらって
Wait, wait, wait, hold your axis more.
もう軸をもち...はい、びしっと。パッパッパラッパッパッパラッ...こうね？
Hold your axis... Yes, sharply. Pa-pa-para-pa-pa-para... like this?
そしたら、手は、手はこう、ぴょっこ、ぴょっこね。で広げ過ぎないように、ぴょっこぴょっこね。そうそうそうそう...
Then, hands are like this, pyokko pyokko. And so as not to spread too much, pyokko pyokko. Yeah, yeah, yeah...
あなたの可愛いじゃん。こうね？こうね？あ、そうそうそうそう...
Yours is cute. Like this? Like this? Ah, yes, yes, yes...
どっちの足出すとかわかんなくなっちゃう。
I don't know which foot to put out anymore.
で、えっと、はい、右足を付くときに、こう手を下げる。
And, um, yes, when placing the right foot, lower your hands like this.
え？いって意味わかる？うん、
Eh? Do you know what I mean? Yeah,
ざっくりで言うと、左足を上げたときに、えっと...下げる。
broadly speaking, when you lift your left foot, um... lower them.
オケー？大丈夫？
Okay? Are you okay?
こう？あーまあそんな感じでいいや。
Like this? Ah well, that's fine.
こうね？おっけーおっけー。パッパッパラッパッパッパラッ...
Like this? Okay, okay. Pa-pa-para-pa-pa-para...
で、パッパッて2回続けるの。
And do "pa-pa" twice continuously.
そしたら、パッパッパラッパッ...で、顔の前で、パッパッて手を振る。そうそうそう！
Then, pa-pa-para-pa... and in front of your face, wave your hands pa-pa. Yeah, yeah, yeah!
で、そんときに肘ごといくと大げさになっちゃうから、手首だけでパッパッ。
And at that time, if you go with your elbows, it becomes exaggerated, so just with your wrists, pa-pa.
白いから見づらい。テレビのとこ行って。こう？あ、そうそうそう、上手上手。
Because it's white, it's hard to see. Go to the TV. Like this? Ah, yeah, yeah, good job.
そしたら、方向転換して、
Then, change direction,
方向転換したら、同じことをやる。パッパッパラッパッ...こう！パッパッ、そうそうそれでいいや。
once you change direction, do the same thing. Pa-pa-para-pa... like this! Pa-pa, yeah, that's fine.
で、こうね？そうそうそう。
And like this? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
それが、パッパッパラッパッパッパラッパッパラッパッパッパッパッてできました！
That is: pa-pa-para-pa-pa-para-pa-para-pa-pa-pa! We did it!
じゃあ、前向いて...
Then, face forward...
クルりん、クルりん、クルりん、クルりん。
Kururin, kururin, kururin, kururin.
で、そんときは、肩ごといくと大げさになっちゃうから、肘、肘を軸にして、くる、くるって上に持ってくよ。できた！
And at that time, if you go with your shoulders it gets too exaggerated, so with your elbows as the axis, bring it up kuru, kuru. Done!
そう、できた、天才！
Yeah, we did it, genius!
そしたら、反対も同じことをクル、クルって持ってく。おおー！これできる！
Then, do the same thing on the other side, bring it kuru, kuru. Ohh! We can do this!
できちゃった。そしたら、両手を、ターン、ターン、ターン、ターン、こうね？そう、天才！
We did it! Then, both hands, turn, turn, turn, turn, like this? Yeah, genius!
すごーい！
So amazing!
なんでもできるじゃん！
You can do anything!
やったね！やったね！嬉しい嬉しい！すごいすごい！
Yay! Yay! So happy! Amazing, amazing!
で、それができたら、クル、クル、クル、クル、ターン、ターン、ターン、ターン、もう一回同じことやる。
And once you can do that, kururin, kururin, kururin, kururin, turn, turn, turn, turn, do the same thing one more time.
クル、クル、クル、クル、ターン、ターン、ターン、ターン、はい。
Kururin, kururin, kururin, kururin, turn, turn, turn, turn, yes.
そしたらね、前に、右足踏んで、こう、右足踏んで、ぐ、パンってやる。窓を開けるみたいな。
Then, step forward with your right foot, like this, step with your right foot, gu, and go pan. Like opening a window.
ぐ、パンってやって、ターンするよ。
Gu, pan, and turn.
ターンすんの？そうそうそう、待って、パンツ見た？今？もう見ちゃダメ。
You turn? Yeah, yeah, wait, did you see my panties? Just now? Don't look anymore.
で、パンってやるときに、こんときに顔だけ残すと可愛い、こうやって。見てて。こうやってやるのと、こうやってやるのだと、顔だけ残したほうが可愛く見えるでしょ？可愛い！
And when you do pan, leaving just your face looks cute, like this. Watch. Doing it like this versus doing it like this, leaving just your face makes it look cuter, right? Cute!
ちゃんちょんもそのようにやりたい。
Chon-chyon wants to do it that way too.
だから、顔だけ残す。
So, leave just your face.
そうそうそうそう、でもオッケーオッケーオッケー。そう！オッケーだね！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, but okay, okay, okay. Yeah! That's okay!
で、うん、パンって後ろ向いたら、後ろ向いて、右手 腰に当てて、左手を、やっほー、やっほー、やっほー。
And when you turn back with pan, turn back, put your right hand on your waist, and your left hand, yaho, yaho, yaho.
だってさ
Like...
そうそうそうそうそう、それを
Right, right, right, right. So,
えっと、えーっとね、
um, let's see,
うち外だとしたら、うち外、うち、うち
if it's inside-outside, then inside-outside, inside, inside,
うち、外、うち、うち、外、うち
inside, outside, inside, outside, inside.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
そしたらもう一回同じこと、うん、ぱんってやって
Then do the exact same thing again, boom, like that,
うち見たら、うち外うちってやるよ。
and when you look inside, it's inside, outside, inside.
うち外うち
Inside, outside, inside.
そう。
Right.
そこまではとりあえずオッケーかな？
Up to there is okay for now, right?
もう一回やってみようか、パッパパラから。
Let's try it again from the pa-pa-para.
音楽流れるの？
Does the music play?
音楽は流さないでいこう。
Let's go without playing the music.
わかった。
Got it.
いくよ。ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー！ワン、ツー、スリー、ハー！
Here we go. One, two, three, four! One, two, three, ha!
パッパパラ、パッパパラ、パッパパラ、パッパパラ、パッパ！
Pa-pa-para, pa-pa-para, pa-pa-para, pa-pa-para, pa-pa!
くるくるくるくるくるくるどん！どん！くるくるくるくるくるくるきのこたん！
Kuru-kuru-kuru-kuru-kuru-kuru-don! Don! Kuru-kuru-kuru-kuru-kuru-kuru-kinoko-tan!
さあ、次行くよ。うん、ぱーん、はい、はい！
Now, next part. Um, boom, yes, yes!
うち、外、うち！うん、ぱーん！
Inside, outside, inside! Um, boom!
うち、外、うち！
Inside, outside, inside!
あ、でもね、大丈夫。
Ah, but hey, it's alright.
形としてはすごい良い感じ。
The form looks really good.
できたー！
We did it!
いい感じだね。
It's going well.
すごいって言われてる。ほんと？
They're saying it's amazing. Really?
そんな感じです。えっと画面の前の皆さんもね、今一緒に踊ってると思うんでね、踊ってください最後、一緒に。
That's how it is. Everyone watching, I think you're dancing along too, so please dance along at the end.
踊りましょう、一緒に。はい、ダンシングタイム！アイドルなんで皆さんも。
Let's dance together. Yes, dancing time! Since we're idols, everyone too.
そうそう。はい、そしたらですね、えっとね、えーと、たらたー、たらたらたー、たら、てれれれれー
Right, right. Yes, and then, um, let's see, ta-ra-ta, ta-ra-ta-ra-ta, ta-ra, te-re-re-re-re...
アーマークて、だね。
Armor-kuthe, right.
そしたら、ちょっとここから難しいんだけど、こうなってるじゃん。
Then, it gets a bit tricky from here, but it's like this.
ふん。なってたら
Hmm. Once it's like that,
こっちにぐっ
you go this way—
なんか音変じゃない？
Wait, isn't the audio weird?
ん？
Hm?
ん？直った？
Hm? Did it fix?
なんか音変だよ。
The audio sounds weird.
なんか入った？なんか入った？
Did something get in? Did something get in?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
なんか、マイクがね、マイク変にー
Like, the mic... the mic is acting weird—
怖いよ、怖いこと起きないようにしてくださいね。音が、音が近い。
It's scary, please don't let anything scary happen. The audio is too close.
はい。大丈夫かな？
Right. Is it okay?
今って船長？
Is Marine-senchou right now?
まつりちゃん普通？
Matsuri-chan normal?
まつりちゃんはね、なんもないけど。
Matsuri-chan is, well, nothing's wrong.
なんか変な感じした。ほらこう、コメントも変って言ってる。
It felt weird. Look, comments are saying it's weird too.
え、船長の？あれでも全然違う。
Eh, Senchou's? Oh wait, it's completely different.
だって遠いもん、マイクいっちゃう。
Because it's far, the mic went somewhere.
じゃあ、じゃあ行きましょうか。はい、気にせずにいきましょう。わかりました。はい。うち外うちってやりましたら、この手を、こうやって持っていきます。
Well then, shall we go? Right, let's go without worrying about it. Understood. Yes. When you do inside, outside, inside, you bring this hand like this.
え？こう？ぐらんって持って行くと同時に1歩こう踏み出す。
Eh? Like this? As you bring it around in a grand sweep, you take a step out.
え、難しいよ、それは。
Eh, that's difficult.
えーとね、見てってじゃん。いくよ。見てて、体。
Um, watch, right? Here we go. Watch my body.
わかった。
Got it.
これをこう。そんだけ。
This, like this. That's all.
足だけだから。こうなってたら、こうやっていくだけ。
Just the feet. If it's like this, you just go like this.
こう？あ、右足の方に左足を置いてく。
Like this? Ah, you place your left foot toward your right foot.
ん？ん？
Hm? Hm?
今ね、前向いてもらって、前向ける？
Right now, face forward, can you face forward?
前向いて、前向いて。
Face forward, face forward.
あれ？これマイク入ってる？なんかマイクなんか変だよ。
Huh? Is the mic on? The mic sounds kind of weird.
大丈夫かな？ほら変って言われてる。
Is it okay? Look, people are saying it's weird.
ね、やっぱ変だよね。まつりなんかめちゃめちゃ響いてる。
Right, it is weird. Matsuri, it's echoing like crazy.
あ、直った？ん？
Ah, did it fix? Hm?
あ、あ、あ、あ、あ、あ、直ったんじゃない？
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, didn't it fix?
あ、大丈夫かな？船長の音声が入ってなかったって。
Ah, is it okay? They said Senchou's audio wasn't coming through.
あ、なるほどね。なるほど。行きますよ。はい。
Ah, I see. Understood. Here we go. Yes.
そしたら、まず全身見てもらって、はい、前向いた状態で
Then, first check the whole body, yes, facing forward,
右足の方にこう踏み込んで、右足をどんって踏み込みながらこうやって方向転換する。
step into your right foot, and while stamping your right foot down, change direction.
こうね？そしたら、手を一緒にこうやってやるだけ。
Like this? Then you just do this with your hands together.
あ、えーとね、こうなってるから、内側かな？内側に流れるようにこう持ってく。
Ah, let's see, since it's like this, is it inside? You bring it so it flows inward like this.
こう。そうそうそう！そう！
Like this. Right, right, right! Yes!
あれ？あ、外だねそれは。内側にこうか。そうそうそう。
Huh? Ah, that's outside. Inward like this. Right, right, right.
うーん、難しい。で、できた。こうだ。できた。おっけーすごい。
Ugh, difficult. There, done. Like this. Done. Okay, amazing.
天才、天才だよ。
Genius, you're a genius.
天才？ほら、ほら、ほら。
Genius? Look, look, look.
あ、それ。あ、でも、こう、オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。大丈夫、大丈夫。
Ah, that. Ah, but, like, okay, okay, okay. It's fine, it's fine.
はい。あ、そうそうそう。そしたら腰に手を当てて。
Yes. Ah, right, right, right. Then put your hands on your hips.
右、左。右、左。
Right, left. Right, left.
あ、そう、で、その時に左足残しとく。右、左。
Ah, right, and at that time, leave your left foot behind. Right, left.
そしたらもう回左にこうやって踏み込んで方向転換。
Then step into the left again like this and change direction.
こう。そうそうそう。そしたら、右、左。
Like this. Right, right, right. Then, right, left.
右、左！踏み込んで、踏み込んで、右、左を、これを4回繰り返します。
Right, left! Step in, step in, right, left, repeat this 4 times.
それを歌に合わせると、はい。アーマークて幸せのこと、隠し味にしてしようになります。
When you match that to the song, yes. 'Armor-kuthe happiness, make it a secret ingredient' becomes that.
あ、でもね、できてる。ほんと？できてできてる。できてきてる。
Ah, but hey, you got it. Really? It's working, it's working.
練習してるの、頑張ってるの伝わるから。ま、でもね、全然大丈夫。
I can tell you're practicing hard and trying your best. Well, even so, it's totally fine.
よし、じゃあこのままいきましょう。うん。もうとにかく完成させよ、完成させよ。
Alright, then let's go with this. Yeah. Let's just finish it up, finish it up.
何にしようの時に何にしようって考えてもらう。
When it's 'what shall we make it,' have them think about what to make.
一番最後だね。
It's the very last part.
かーかーいち、に、いち、
Ka-ka-ichi, ni, ichi,
かーかーいち、に、
Ka-ka-ichi, ni,
いち、次考えるよ。
Ichi, next we'll think about it.
そう考えて
Think about it like this,
こう、そう、こしゃくダンス
Like this, right, the Koshaku Dance.
そう、そこまではオッケー
Right, up to there is okay.
だいぶ来た、だいぶ来たよ
We're getting somewhere, getting somewhere.
来た？
Really?
そしたら、「何にしよー」で純粋なんだけど、こうなってるじゃん。
Then, for "What should I do?", it's innocent, but it's like this.
なんかこうなってるじゃん？
Like, it ends up like this, right?
船長休憩できますか？
Captain, can we take a break?
やだ！
No!
休憩させてよ！
Let me take a break!
やだ！
No!
やめてはじめて！
Stop it, start over!
もう、え、JKにもどされないでください！まっかしてたのに！
Geez, don't drag me back to being a JK! I was relaxing!
休憩休憩を
Break, break...
なんか回線落ちたみたいなんで、休憩しました。
My connection seemed to drop, so we took a break.
したしたね。
We did, we did.
いや、復活した、もうガンガン踊るよ！
No, I'm revived, let's dance full out!
行くよ、もう元気！
Let's go, I'm full of energy!
元気発ラツ！
Full of energy!
そうですね、動いてるとまた疲れちゃうから。そうですね。
That's right, if we keep moving we'll get tired again. True.
じゃあ、あんまり動かないようにします。
Well then, I'll try not to move too much.
じゃあ、まずさっきのとかまで覚えているかな？
Well then, do you remember up to what we did earlier?
ちょっと復習しようか、パッパッパラから。
Let's do a little review, starting from pa-pa-ppara.
行くよ！
Here we go!
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー、ワン、ツー、スリー、はい！
One, two, three, four, one, two, three, go!
パッパッパラ、パッパッパラ…
Pa-pa-ppara, pa-pa-ppara...
タンタンタンタン、ハイハイ…
Tan tan tan tan, hai hai...
ちゃんちゃんちゃんちゃん、ハイハイ…
Chan chan chan chan, hai hai...
うん、ぽん！タラタラ…タラタラ…
Un, pon! Tara tara... tara tara...
甘味って、どこどこ…隠し味、何にしよう、純粋、乙女ごころまでね。
Sweet love, where, where... secret ingredient, what should I make it, innocent, up to a maiden's heart.
こしゃくダンスって言われてるけど…
They call it the Koshaku Dance, but...
こしゃくダンスって…
The Koshaku Dance...
どういうことじゃん、こしゃくダンスが踊れってのはすごいことなんだぞ！
What do you mean, being able to dance the Koshaku Dance is amazing!
体力なくちゃできませんよー！
You can't do it without stamina!
じゃあ、「乙女ごころ」までいきました。そしたら、ハートを作ります。
Well then, we got up to 'maiden's heart'. Next, we make a heart.
オッケー！
Okay!
甘い恋もーん
Sweet sweet love...
そうそうそう、ハートを作りました。
That's right, we made a heart.
甘い恋もで右、左です。
With 'sweet sweet love', it's right, then left.
そしたら、「からめなっちゃ」で前にハートを出していく。
Then, with 'get entangled', you push the heart forward.
後ろにあるのね？胸のとこにあるから、「みんな見なりとげー」って、「からめなっちゃ」ってやったら。
It's in the back? It's on your chest, so when you say 'everyone look at me' and do 'get entangled'.
きまずい、今の空気。
Awkward, the atmosphere right now.
そしたら、こっちにもう一回同じことをこうやっていって…
Then, do the same thing over here like this...
重ねて、ミルフィーユのときに「1、2、3」ってやるんだけど…
Layering it, when it's 'Mille-feuille' you do '1, 2, 3'...
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
あのね、タンタンタンってやる。「こう」じゃなくて、手首を乗せる、乗せる、乗せる…！
You know, you do tan tan tan. Not 'like this', but put your wrist on, put it on, put it on...!
はい、できた！みてみて！それでいいや！
Alright, done! Look look! That's fine!
からめなっちゃ…
Get entangled...
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと
Always, always, always, always...
ターン、てね？
A turn, right?
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと
Always, always, always, always...
ターン、てん。
A turn, ten.
ここまで同じさっきだ。
It's the same as before up to here.
あれっ？
Huh?
今度は、さっきこっちに行ったけど、今度はこっちに行く。
This time, we went that way before, but now we go this way.
オッケー、こっちね。そうそうそう、反対のやつ。
Okay, this way. Right, the opposite one.
そしたらもう一回ターン、ターン、ターン、ターン、やる。
Then do another turn, turn, turn, turn.
オッケー、ここまで大丈夫かな？ ばっちりです。
Okay, is everything alright so far? Perfect.
オッケーオッケー、できるじゃん。
Okay, okay, you can do it.
もう体力、さっきはね、画面のタイキックで死んだだけであって、本当はこのくらいは余裕なんです。
As for stamina, we just died from the screen's Thai kick earlier, this is actually a breeze.
余裕？
A breeze?
じゃ、ここまで曲つけてできる？
Can we do this with music up to here?
やろう！ 1回曲つけてやりますか、じゃあ。行きましょう！
Let's do it! Shall we add the music for once? Let's go!
じゃあ行きますよ。曲流しますかね？
Here we go. Shall we play the music?
最初どういうポーズだっけ？
What was the starting pose again?
え、一番始めはこうやって構えてる。
Um, at the very beginning, we pose like this.
そうそう！
That's right!
かわいい、構えが天才！ うん、これはね17歳って言ってもみんな騙されるよ。
Cute, the pose is genius! Everyone will be fooled into thinking we're 17.
さあ、やりましょうね。
Now then, let's do it.
それでは行きましょう！ メジック、スタート！
Let's go! Magic start!
ねぇ、あなたの名前を 呼ぶたび
Hey, every time I call out your name,
甘い匂いがしてくる ふしぎだね
I wonder why such a sweet scent comes over me.
ねぇ、そばにいなくても 話しかけている
Hey, even when you're not by my side, I'm talking to you,
心のなかでは いつでも
always from the bottom of my heart.
大好きな人に 大好きだって 伝えられる しあわせ
The happiness of being able to tell the one I love how much I love them
がんばって生きてきた ごほうびかもね
might be the reward for living hard.
la la la...
ねぇ、次の交差点 手をつなごう
Hey, at the next intersection, let's hold hands.
って、もう 連れ去りたいのに ここから
Though I already want to take you away from here,
ねぇ、そこにいるだけで カンペキなんです
hey, just being there is already perfect.
心配 いらない なにも
There's nothing to worry about at all.
大好きな人に 大好きだって 伝えられる しあわせ
The happiness of being able to tell the one I love how much I love them
がんばって生きていく ごほうびかもね
might be the reward for continuing to live.
できちゃった！
We did it!
え？
Huh?
だいぶできてますよ。
We've got most of it down.
あのー、お姉さん？
Um, big sister?
でもね、もうね、大体半分くらいはできましたよ。
But you know, we've already got about half of it done.
あ、ですよね！
Ah, right!
よろしい。
Good.
あとちょっと頑張りほしい。
Need you to try a little harder.
お母さん頑張れだって。
"Mom, do your best," they say.
お母さん... お母さんじゃなくて！
Mom... Not mom!
お姉さんだろう、しょうがない。
It's big sister, oh well.
つん。
Poke.
きっつ！
So harsh!
きっつい、きっつい、あんなのって。
That's way too harsh.
あね、今の17歳は！
Hey, today's 17-year-olds!
あね、今の17歳はつんとかしないから。
Today's 17-year-olds don't go around poking people.
何するのじゃあ？
Then what do they do?
え、何もしない、そんなの変な動き。
Um, nothing, that's such a weird move.
ぴょん！
Pyon!
やめる、かわいい、おもしろい。
Stop it, it's cute, it's funny.
だって、なんて言われたいの、逆に？ ぴょんって言ったときに。
I mean, what do you want people to say when you go "pyon"?
え、かわいい！
"So cute!"
かわいすぎ！ かわいすぎる！
Too cute! Way too cute!
分かった、オッケー、それで行くわ、今後。
Got it, okay, I'll go with that from now on.
うん。
Yeah.
次行くわね。次ぴょんって言ったらそれ使うからよろしくお願いしますね。
Here we go next. If I say "pyon" next time, I'll use that, so please play along.
かしこまりました。うん。
Understood. Yeah.
えと、えと、ねぇ、交差点なくちゃ、までいったら、
Um, um, hey, once we reach "intersection,"
ここがステップちょっとさっき難しいって言ってたやつなんだよね、船長が。
this is the step the Captain said was a bit difficult earlier.
はい。
Yes.
なんだけっけ？ たんたんたん、あ、たんたんたん、にやるの。
What was it again? Tan-tan-tan, ah, do it like tan-tan-tan.
ええと、
Um,
外に蹴る。蹴って、蹴って、蹴って。
kick outward. Kick, kick, kick.
たん、たん、あ、そうそうそう、今できてた、今できてた。
Tan, tan, ah, right, right, you were doing it just now.
今できてたよ。蹴って、
You were doing it just now. Kick,
お、足替えて、落とす。足替えて、落とす。
oh, switch feet and drop. Switch feet and drop.
もっと簡単なほうのステップにする？
Should we use an easier step?
こことさ、どっちがいいかな？ こう。あ、そっちの方が簡単だね。じゃ、そっちに、そっちのバージョンで行きましょう。はい。
Which one is better? Like this. Ah, that's easier. Let's go with that version. Okay.
蹴る。おろす。おろすこいって言われてるけど。
Kick. Drop. Drop, they say.
で、大丈夫、無視無視。まずそんなの落とすって言われてる。
But it's fine, ignore it. They're telling us to drop it first.
無視無視！ そう、無視無視。
Ignore it! Right, ignore it.
さんの、全然聞いてないもーん。きかないよー。
San, you're not listening at all. I won't listen!
聞いてる聞いてる！ 聞いてる聞いてる！
I am listening! I am listening!
やめて！ 聞いてる聞いてる！ 聞かないっていうか、大体聞いてるから。
Stop it! I'm listening! Not that I don't listen, I mostly listen.
ひろちゃ時点聞いてるからね。
I'm listening from Hiro-chan's perspective.
無視できないやつね。
One you can't ignore.
えーと、じゃあステップ今の覚えられた？ ちょっとやってみてよ。
Um, so did you memorize the step just now? Try doing it.
はい、たんたんたんだよ。1、2、3。
Yes, it's tan-tan-tan. 1, 2, 3.
えとね、1歩で行こうとしちゃってるから、1、2、3ってやってみて。
Um, you're trying to do it in one step, so try doing 1, 2, 3.
1、2、3、1、2、3。
1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3.
右、右、左。右、右、左。
Right, right, left. Right, right, left.
左はね、上げなくていい。後ろにパッとやるだけ。
You don't need to lift the left. Just pop it back.
なるほどね！ 右、右、左。うん、そうそうそうそう。右、右、左。
I see! Right, right, left. Yeah, exactly. Right, right, left.
こう、そうそうそう。たんたんたん、たったたん、たったたん。できた！
Like this, yes. Tan-tan-tan, ta-ta-tan, ta-ta-tan. We did it!
それを、えーとね、4回くらい？ 6、6かな？
And we do that about, um, 4 times? 6, 6 maybe?
まじ？
Seriously?
まず、手を上、上、下、下
First, put your hands up, up, down, down,
のやつを1、2、3ってやる。
and then do 1, 2, 3 like this.
1、2、3、はい、はい、本体も1、2、3
1, 2, 3, right, right, body too, 1, 2, 3.
1、2、3
1, 2, 3.
そしたら、えっと 手を、こ、こうやって持ってくの、を、この間にやるんだけど
Then, um, you bring your hands like this... you do it in between,
ちょっと流してやると、たん、たん、たん…に鳴るの。
but if you flow through it, it goes tan, tan, tan...
どうしたらいいかな？どうしたらいいかな？
What should I do? What should I do?
いや、こ、こう…こういうことしょ？
No, l-like... something like this, right?
良くないよ！
That's no good!
同じじゃん！見た目。
It looks the exact same!
ほら。
Look.
ま、船長が今後このアーカイブが残って、それが残るでもいいならいいよ。
Well, Captain, if you're fine with this archive staying around forever, then it's fine.
練習し始めちゃった…
She started practicing...
流してよ、なんか、リズム乗っちゃえばさ、バレないんじゃないかな？
Just flow with it, if you catch the rhythm, won't it not be noticeable?
そうだね。
That's true.
多少変なのは、バレないから手だけじゃ覚えようか。
Minor weirdness won't be noticed, so let's just memorize the hands.
はい。上、下、上、下
Okay. Up, down, up, down.
なんだ？ラジオ体操みたい。
What is this? It's like radio calisthenics.
これを2回繰り返すよ。上、下、上、下で繰り返したら
Repeat this twice. Up, down, up, down, and if you repeat it,
手を前にこう持ってきて、胸に持ってくる。
you bring your hands forward like this, and bring them to your chest.
はい。これは船長できる？
Okay. Can you do this, Captain?
できた。
I did it.
そしたら、くるくるって回しながら外に、くるくるパン、くるくる内、くるくる外、くるくる内ってやる。
Then, spin them around while moving outward—spin, clap, spin in, spin out, spin in.
それを足に合わせてやると、たん、たん、たん…に鳴るの。
If you match that with your feet, it goes tan, tan, tan...
できた！
I did it!
おっけー、できたね。
Okay, you did it.
できたんでことにしとこう。コロンビア。
Let's say you did it. Colombia.
できましたらですね、それができたらもうね、怖いものなんてありません。
Once you can do that, there's nothing to be afraid of anymore.
おー！
Oh!
甘さを抑えてピーターパンとか、ミルク味のコーヒーとか
Holding back the sweetness, like Peter Pan, or coffee with a milky taste,
こう、上に手を持ってきます。甘いだけじゃ
bring your hands up like this. Sweetness alone...
はい。そしたら、頭の後ろで…そうそう、それを2回こうやって上から持ってきてあげるだけ。
Okay. Then behind your head... right, right, you just bring them down from above twice like this.
効くわ。
It really works.
この動きしてね、そんなおばさんになりたくなった人初めて見たから。効く、これ肩に効くわ。
I've never seen anyone want to look like such an old lady doing this. It works, it works on your shoulders.
甘いだけじゃ言葉に…そう、前に持ってって、できないの。
Sweetness alone in words... Right, bring it forward, "I can't do it."
それをあんまりこうやってやると大袈裟の幼稚園児みたいになっちゃうから。
If you exaggerate it too much like this, you look like an over-the-top kindergartener.
脱線…あ、すいません。水槽の骨が
Derail... ah, sorry. The bone of the aquarium...
ちっちゃくこの場で。はい、ここでね、ちっちゃく、こんな感じ？
Small, right here. Okay, right here, small, like this?
それをやるときに、右、左、右って足を…そうそうそうそう。右、左、右で終わり。
When doing that, right, left, right with your feet... right, right, right. Right, left, right, and finish.
甘さを抑えてピーターあとから、ミルク味のコーヒーとか甘いだけじゃ大人になれないの。です。
"Holding back the sweetness, like Peter Pan, or coffee with a milky taste, you can't be an adult with just sweetness." That's it.
そんなの絶対に嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ…大人になれないの、ここ、そんなの、ここ、絶対に、ここ、くるりん、で、嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ。
You say "I absolutely don't want that, no way..." "I can't become an adult, here, no way, here, absolutely, here, spin, and no, no, no, no."
船長は…それでもいいや。船長はこうやって嫌だ嫌だやってればいい。わかりました。
Captain... well, that's fine too. Captain can just do "no, no, no" like this. Understood.
そしたら、あのパッパパラに戻ります。パッパパラパッパパラパッパパラパッパパ！
Then, we go back to the pa-pa-para. Pa-pa-para-pa-pa-para!
ねぇ、あげようか、になるんで、方向転換してこっち…ねぇ、こう、あ、そうそうそう！
Then it becomes "Hey, shall we raise it?", so change direction and go this way... hey, like this, ah, right, right, right!
そのときにね、大体の人こうやってしゃがむだけなんだけど、船長はこうやってたじゃん。これがちょっと
At that time, most people just squat down like this, but Captain was doing it like this. That's a bit...
ねぇ、パン！て言うんで、ねぇ、パン！ねぇタン、たらた、たー。こー、あいーんってやればいい。
When saying "Hey, bam!", "Hey, bam!", "Hey tan, tarata, taー." Just do "a-in" like this.
きゅいーん！楽しいね。きゅいーん！そうそうそう、できてる！
Kyu-iin! That's fun. Kyu-iin! Right, right, you're doing it!
ててて 上いって
Te-te-te, go up,
前いって 胸に持ってく
go forward, bring it to your chest.
ここまでオッケー？
Up to here, okay?
オッケーオッケー
Okay, okay.
そしたら足をこうやって上げまして
Then, lift your leg like this
うん 突き出して 突き出して
and thrust it out, thrust it out.
こう内から外にこう ぐるりぐるりぐるりーんって一緒します
And go round and round from inside to outside together.
あ、効くねこれ
Ah, this really works.
ラジオ体操でよくありますよね
You often see this in radio calisthenics, right?
ぐるりぐるりぐるりーんって一周したら
Once you go round and round in a full circle,
一緒しました？
did you do it?
しましたしました
Yes, we did, we did.
今度はこっちに向かって、うん、ぱーんってこうやって
Now, facing this way, um, like bam you go
落ちます そう、滝みたいな感じね
and drop down. Yeah, like a waterfall.
滝ね
A waterfall.
落ちたら、そのまま顔から、うん、普通にこうやって上げていっちゃうとダサいから
Once you drop, if you just bring it up straight from your face, it looks lame, so
こうやって上がる
you rise up like this.
あ、そうそうそうそう、首からこうやって
Ah, right right right, from the neck like this,
ウェーブみたいな
like a wave.
そうそうそう、でもできてりよ！
Right right, but you're doing it!
できて る！
I am!
できてるできてるところ
You're doing it, you're doing it.
オッケー、ここまで覚えられそう？
Okay, can you remember up to here?
うん、よゆうよゆう
Yeah, piece of cake.
どこからできそう？
From where can you do it?
全部通す？ 全部通す？
Run through the whole thing? Run through it?
えーっと
Umm...
なれないの、そんなの、絶対に、絶対に、
You can't get used to it, definitely not,
いやだいやだいやだ パッパパラパッパパラパッパパラパッパパ
definitely no way, no way! Pa-pa-para pa-pa-para...
ねえ 上げよう お金
Hey, let's raise it!
いいわな
Sounds nice.
ほら とりこにしてあげる
Look, I'll make you captivated.
どんな魔法 パーン 上げるから
What kind of magic? Bam, because I'll raise it up!
そしたら ここで指を顔の前に持ってきて人差し指を立てます
Then, bring your finger in front of your face and hold up your index finger.
うん
Yeah.
そしたら、えっと、ターン、ターン、ターン、トーンってちょっと後ろに下がる
Then, um, turn, turn, turn, ton, you step back a bit.
かね？
Right?
そうそうそう そしたらあとはもう うん、うん、ぱーんってこうやって広げて回ると終わり
Right right, and then just, um, spread out with a bam and spin around, and it's done.
できたー！
We did it!
終わり これでもう一応終わりです
That's it. That's basically the end of it.
いけます
We can do it.
いけるよね
You can do it, right?
覚えた
I memorized it.
いけてるよねねえ
You're doing great, right?
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
いけてると思うよ 皆さん応援ありがとう これビフォーアフターが楽しみですね
I think you're doing great. Thanks for cheering us on, everyone. I'm looking forward to the before and after.
最初のね踊れなかった頃の船長と今の踊れるようになった船長
The captain who couldn't dance at first, and the captain who can dance now...
いえーい ねー で、じゃあ一回はじめから音ありでここで練習してアップでおひろめにしようか
Yay! Hey, so let's practice it once from the beginning with audio here and show it off in closeup.
あ、じゃあいきましょうか これで満足ですか？
Ah, shall we go then? Are you satisfied with this?
そんなこと言うなよ パンチパンチ、船長が元気だったらマジ仮面ライダーキック飛んでるよ今
Don't say that! Punch punch, if the captain had energy right now, Kamen Rider kick would be flying.
この画面端からね ミュージック
From the edge of this screen, music!
元気が余ってればねやったよ でも元気や...
If I had energy left, I would've done it. But my energy is...
立たのき扇風機曲もやろう、この画面端から 立つタヌキ扇風機曲
Let's also do the standing tanuki electric fan song, from the edge of this screen...
じゃあ船長1人でやってもらおうかな 1人じゃ無理か
Well, should we have the captain do it alone? Is alone too hard?
1人じゃ無理です 1人じゃ無理か じゃあ今戻ってください
Alone is impossible. Is alone too hard? Well, please come back now.
体力消耗したけど大丈夫ですか？ すぐじゃ... すぐじゃ...
You consumed your stamina, but are you okay? Immediately...
さっきのタヌキ扇風機曲キッチインだって
They said the tanuki electric fan song was neat earlier.
パッパパラパッパパラパッパパラパッパパー
Pa-pa-para, pa-pa-para, pa-pa-para, pa-pa-paa
全力ガカッコイイ 夢中で駆け抜けろ
Looking cool at full throttle, running through in a trance!
世界中を味方にしてキメよう Ride On My Fire!
Make the whole world your ally and nail it, Ride On My Fire!
そうだろう？
Right?
たまに負けるのは 強くなるため
Sometimes losing is just to become stronger.
現実ってヤツは 実力だけがモノ云う世界
Reality is a world where only raw ability speaks.
諦めることは容易いけれども 熱くなれるコト
Giving up is easy, but just having something you can be passionate about...
持ってるだけで凄くないんじゃ無い
doesn't mean you're amazing on its own.
フィールド広げろ 次のカードはBlack or White?
Expand your field, what's the next card? Black or White?
何処にだって 誰にだって 目指す場所がある
Anywhere, anyone, there's a place to aim for.
行くぜ もっと上に GO!
Let's go, higher still, GO!
全力ガカッコイイ 夢中で駆け抜けろ
Looking cool at full throttle, running through in a trance!
好きなものは 好きだと 貫いて
Stick to what you love, saying I love it!
切札は「自分」さ 呼び覚ませ本能を
Your trump card is yourself, awaken your instincts!
ダメージさえ味方にしてキメよう Ride on My Fire! そうだろう?
Make even damage your ally and nail it, Ride on My Fire! Right?
逡巡な脆さで 自分疑う
Doubting yourself with hesitant fragility,
認めることより 中傷ばかり溢れる世界
a world overflowing with slanders rather than recognition.
貶めることは容易いけれども ホントの事だけ
Belittling others is easy, but only the truth...
信じることが「強さ」だろう
believing in it is strength, right?
まばゆく蹴散らせ 彼の運命Black or White?
Dazzlingly scatter them, that destiny, Black or White?
過去にだって 未来だって 変化わるチャンスがある
Whether in the past or the future, there is a chance to change.
目指せ もっと上に GO!
Aim higher, GO!
疲れって…まだお披露目じゃないんですけど
I'm not even debuting yet, but I'm tired...
わかってます！わかってます！
I know, I know!
ちょっと疲れたふりしてただけ
I was just pretending to be tired.
本当？
Really?
なるほどね。ふりね。ふりふり。
I see. Pretending, huh. Just pretending.
本当疲れてないもんね？
You're not really tired, right?
ちょっと心配しないで！
Hey, don't worry!
何歳だっけ？
How old are you again?
17歳。
17 years old.
本当は？
Really?
ごめんなさい、ごめんなさい、ごめんなさい…
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
よし！お茶飲もうお茶！
Alright! Let's drink some tea!
お水タイムしましょうか
Let's take a water break.
皆さんもね、パソコンの前、スマホの前でダンスレッスンしてると思うんですけど、しっかり水分補給はしましょう！よろしくお願いします！
I'm sure you guys are doing dance lessons in front of your PCs and phones too, so make sure to stay hydrated! Please look forward to it!
先生っぽい今日のお祭り。
Matsuri looks like an instructor today.
実際ね、ダンスの先生ですからね、祭先輩は。今日はね、今日だけね。
Actually, Matsuri-senpai is a dance instructor, you know. Today is, well, just for today.
だって、あの豊洲のさ、祭り先輩とか皆さん見ました？
I mean, did you guys see Matsuri-senpai and everyone at Toyosu?
見た？めっちゃ可愛かった。
Did you? She was so cute.
船長さ…
Captain...
船長さ！これさ、祭りの時片手風車って言われて…
Captain! At the festival, people said you had one-armed windmills...
片手風車？マリンは片手風車って言われて…
One-armed windmills? Marine had one-armed windmills...
マリンもそんな変わんないよ。ちょっと、ちょっと一瞬踊って？
Marine isn't that different either. Wait, dance for a second?
え、どこ、どこ、どこ、サビ？
Eh, where, where, where, the chorus?
サビ！サビサビサビやって！どんなんだっけ？ここから…
The chorus! Do the chorus! How did it go? From here...
あ、どこ、音ハメ忘れちゃったんだけど。
Ah, where, I forgot the timing.
「もっと祭りを見て」って、もっと「もっと！」忘れちゃった。
"Watch Matsuri more", more "More!" I forgot.
なんでも、人に向かってさ…
I mean, telling people...
人に向かってさ、怒られるのとかさ、どんどんボコにしといてさ、覚えてないんじゃん、祭り先輩だって。
Telling people off and getting yelled at, and beating us down, yet you don't even remember it, Matsuri-senpai.
いや、覚えた、ちょっと忘れちゃった。ここ、ここまで踊ってるわ。
No, I remembered, I just forgot a bit. I danced up to here.
これ可愛かった。可愛かった、ありがとう。忘れちゃったな。
That was cute. It was cute, thanks. I forgot.
また思い出したら踊ろう。そうしましょう。
Let's dance again when we remember. Let's do that.
じゃあ、わかんないところ逆に、もうちょい時間があるから、ここが分からないってとこがあったら教えましょう。
Then, if there's any part you don't understand, since we have a bit more time, let's teach you if there are parts you're unsure of.
1個か2個くらいなら多分…祭り先輩から見て、ここ直してほしいところある？
If it's one or two things, probably... From Matsuri-senpai's perspective, is there anything you want me to fix?
何、その目は。全部？かな？バシバシ！
What's with that look? All of it? Probably? Smack smack!
船長元気だったら…
Captain, if you were energetic...
船長元気だったらな、ちょっとキックよ！キックキック！マリン今元気だからキックしていい？骨折れちゃうから！
If Captain were energetic, a kick! Kick kick! Marine is energetic right now, so can I kick? You'll break a bone!
でも、がんばりは認めるけど、1時間しかなかったからね。
But, I'll acknowledge your hard work, though we only had an hour.
ていうかすごくない？皆さんちょっとここでさ、イメージを変えてほしい。逆に1時間でここまで踊れちゃうってすごくない？
I mean, isn't that amazing? Everyone, I want you to change your image here. Isn't it amazing to be able to dance this much in just an hour?
やだ、マリンすごすぎ？夢があるよね。
No way, is Marine too amazing? It's dreamy.
祭り先輩、なんか喋ってた？
Matsuri-senpai, were you talking about something?
ログアウトしないで！ちゃんと聞いてて！
Don't log out! Listen properly!
いや、頑張ってたよ、かあちゃん。かあちゃん頑張っ…かあちゃんじゃない！お姉ちゃんでしょ！マリンお姉ちゃんでしょ！
No, you worked hard, mama. Mama worked... Not mama! Big sister, right! Marine big sister!
マリンお姉ちゃんじゃなかった？マリンお姉ちゃんでしょ！こんな可愛いかあちゃんがいてたまるかっつうの。
Wasn't it Marine big sister? It's Marine big sister! As if there's a cute mama like that.
いやいや、かあちゃんでいいよ。
No, no, mama is fine.
じゃあそれぞれね、ステージに行って、その…ドヤ顔で決めれますか？
Then each of us will go to the stage and... can you strike a smug pose?
決めれますよ！
Of course I can!
もちろん！ビフォアアフターみんなね、しっかり見てください。
Of course! Everyone, please make sure to watch the before and after.
ビフォアアフター、あのアーカイブでコメント欄とかにこう時間タイム…載せてもらうと、多分感動しちゃうと思う。
Before and after, if you put timestamps in the comment section in the archive, I think you'll probably get moved.
本当？こんなに踊れる…
Really? To be able to dance this much...
前半はすごいね、上手。なんか1時間でこんなに踊れるようになるもんなのかと、夢がありますね。
The first half is amazing, so good. Makes you wonder if you can dance this much in an hour, it's dreamy.
夢がある。
It's dreamy.
はい。じゃあちょっと、キララジャンプで行けますか？
Yes. So, can we go with Kirara Jump?
最初ね。じゃあ行きますよ！
First. Alright, here we go!
せーの！いぇーい！
Ready, go! Yay!
あれ、来た来た来た！
Wait, it started!
キララジャンプも体力使うからね。
Kirara Jump uses a lot of stamina, so...
3回以上飛ばないでくださいね。
Don't skip more than 3 times, okay?
じゃあ、さっそくいいですか？
Alright, is everyone ready?
ミュージックスタート！それでは皆さん、行きますよ！ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start! Let's go everyone!
ぱっぱっぱっぱ…
Pa pa pa pa...
グルグルグルこさみん！はい！
Spin spin spin, Gurucosamin, yes!
背中がやさしい…はい！はい！はい！はい！
My back is gentle... Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
この内緒…右に行くよ！はい！
This secret... Go to the right, yes!
幸せなこと、ないない！
A happy thing, no, no!
危険なまで匂い立つ
Dangerous marine smell...
❤ahoy❤
これ開けたら君たちになんと言ってあげてべきかな…？
What should I say when you open it...?
「探し育てたのはせ・ん・ち・お？」うーん…
"What were you searching for...?" Um...
「あっかん❤そんなにがっついちゃだめだぞ❤」
"Aha❤ Don't stare so hard, it's no good❤"
かな？
Right?
誘うガーネットの赤
The red of an inviting garter,
極上の海賊の秘宝
the ultimate pirate treasure.
それは私
That is me.
艶が溢れ漂う 匂いをどうかし恐がらないで
Overflowing with charm, don't be scared of the scent,
開けてみて
try opening it.
(アッハッハッハ…❤)
(Ah-hah-hah-hah...❤)
sexy世界一 superピチピチ
Sexy worldwide, super pin-point,
ぶっちぎり船長捕まえたくない？
don't you want to capture the head-turning Captain?
you're gonna get the treasure
maybe tasting me
私の甘さが欲しいんでしょう
Don't you want my sweetness?
(ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
秘宝の鍵を優しく挿して
Gently insert the key to the treasure,
宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
open the vault's door as fast as magic.
(❤ahoy❤)
じれったい貴方の手
Your eager hands,
海図にこぼす甘いため息のtease
tease with sweet sighs spilled on the map.
(yeah…) 純紅のバラがしおれる前に
Before the crimson rose withers,
we will sail the seven seas
(七つの大海を)
(Sailing the seven seas)
summer sun smiling with glee
(股にかけ進め)
(Push forward over the crotch)
shining ocean of marine
(股ってワードからなに想像してんの)
(What are you imagining from the word "crotch"?)
now please grant my dearest dream
open up this box
open it right now or i will scream
(さもないと)
(Or else)
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa!!!!!!!!!!
(あげろおおおおお)
(Open it up, up, up, up, up!)
泣く子も黙るnaughty 悩殺ビーム
Naughty, stunning beam that silences crying children,
キミたちももう我慢できなくならない？ (kaboom…)
can you kids not hold back anymore either? (Kaboom...)
you're gonna own the pleasure
maybe love of me?
私の全てを手に入れて
Get all of me into your hands.
❤❤❤ahhh❤❤❤
(ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
踊れました？船長
Did you enjoy it, Captain?
ていうわけでね 今日本当お疲れ様でした
So, today was truly hard work!
船長？
Captain?
待って10秒
Wait 10 seconds!
なんかあと10秒あるみたいですけど
It seems there are still 10 seconds left, but...
まずねまず今日のを評価をしたいなって思うんですよ
Well, first, I want to grade today's performance.
あ、なるほど
Ah, I see.
評価を、船長の評価を
The rating, Captain's rating.
皆さんと一緒に今日の船長の頑張りとか
Together with everyone, let's think about today's...
ダンスのクオリティとかを考えて
Captain's effort, dance quality, and everything,
えっと評価をしてもらいたいんです、皆さんに。いいですか？
and give a rating, everyone. Is that alright?
95点
95 points.
点数をねつけてもらおうかな100点満点中
I'd like you to give a score. Out of 100 points,
まつりが決める点数とみんなが決める点数
the score determined by Matsuri and the score determined by everyone.
をざっとでコメント見てもらって
Take a quick look at the comments,
まあ、平均点50点以上超えたら、まあいいでしょうと。
and if the average is over 50 points, I guess that's fine?
まあいいでしょう、ご褒美でもなんでも。
Well, that's fine. As a reward or whatever...
50点でいいの？
Is 50 points fine?
50点でいいですよ。
50 points is fine, you know.
それは余裕すぎる。ナメてるか？
That's too generous! Are you looking down on me?
ねえ、もしだめだったら
Hey, if it's no good,
船長はもうここに残ってもらって一人で踊れるまで練習してもらいましょう。
Captain should stay here and practice until she can dance by herself.
え？一生？
Forever?
一生？
うん。
Yeah.
明日から船長ここに1人で住むの？
Starting tomorrow, Captain lives here alone?
ここに住むの。
You're going to live here.
ぴょーん
Pyun!
か、かわいい
C-Cute...
サンキュー
Thank you.
これでもう良くなっちゃった
Already got better.
もう良くなっちゃった、諦めちゃった。
Already got better, gave up.
諦めちゃったかな。きゃわいくいればい。
Gave up, but if it's cute, that's fine.
はい。
Yes!
じゃあまずですね皆さんから点数をざっと見てみましょうか。
Then first, let's take a quick look at everyone's scores.
いいですか船長？
Is that okay, Captain?
みんな！ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
船長アピールポイントを
Captain's appeal point...
じゃあ1分間スピーチどうぞ。
Well, 1-minute speech, please.
せーの、よいスタート！
Ready, set!
ふう、みんなマリン頑張ったんと！
Everyone, Marine worked hard!
いやそれにしてもね、いや1時間でこんなに踊れるようになるものなのかって思っちゃった。
Yeah, even so, to think I could dance this much in just one hour...
でもみんな聞いて、1時間ってすごい短いよ。
Listen everyone, one hour is really short.
じゃあ1時間でみんな踊れるようになるのかっちゅう話。
So can everyone dance in one hour? That's the question.
何、媚びてんじゃんてめえ。
What, you're buttering me up, you idiot!
なに、なに？
What, what?
そう思ったらさ、すごいことだよね船長がここまで踊れるようになってるってのはすごいことだよ。
When you think about it, it's amazing that the Captain can dance this well up to this point, right?
そこをちゃんとね、評価してほしいね、君たちには。
So you should really praise that, you guys.
そのへん考えて。
Think about that.
あれ？ねえ画面、ねえなんか黒くの、あれ？放送事故かな？お帰りか。
Hey, the screen, hey, it's getting dark, huh? Is it about time to go home?
お帰りなさい、お帰りなさーい。
O-帰りなさーい！
というわけで皆さん、今のアピールポイントを聞いてですね、何点をあげたいかなっていうの、えっと、まあ100点満点中
So everyone, after hearing that appeal point, how many points would you like to give?
はい、お願いいたします！
Yes, please!
それではコメントで何点か数字をどうぞお願いします！
So please use comments to give some numbers, please!
にゃん、にゃんにゃんしてね。
Meow, meow...
まつりも
Festival too.
にゃん、あ、痛い！痛いよ！ひっぱたきよ！
H-Hit the clock! Hit it!
10点、2点、40点、-29点、20点
10 points, 2 points, 40 points, -29 points, 20 points...
25点、30点、20点、うーん、船長？
25 points, 30 points, 20 points... Captain?
95点だって。
95 points?
1個しかないよ。
There's only one.
あ、むこう、あ、95点。
Over there, over there.
30点、0点、40点、29点の方が多い。
30 points, 0 points, 40 points, 29 points are more common.
船長！
Captain!
告知があります。
There is an announcement.
今日のダンスレッスン1時間やりました。
Today's dance lesson took one hour.
はい、50点から、50点かなっていうのも来てましたけども、なるほど。
Yes, I came here thinking it would be 50 points or so, but... well.
まつりの、心のなかの点数も含めみんなのやつを平均したところですね、船長の点数は
Matsuri's... including the score from deep inside our hearts, if we average everyone's, well, the Captain's score is...
習ったステップ！習ったステップ！48点！
Taught step! Taught step! Taught step! 48 points!
なんかさ、あのスーパーの特売の、なんか歌手風みたいなさ、ちょっとギリギリ50点行かないのが
Wait, that's like a super special... like a ballad-type score.
いいみたいな、19ぱって最高4点みたいな感じ。そんなさ、なんでそういうことすんの？
It's like, "19", that's the highest score. Why would you do that?
ということね、船長は
So, the Captain...
ダンスがあまり得意ではない。
dance is not really her forte.
あれ？はればれよかになれば踊れるよ？
If she practices hard, she can dance.
あ、じゃあはればれよかちょっと今、あ、はればれよかだからいくよ。ワン、ツー、スリー。
If she practices hard, right now... I want to practice hard, so let's go. One, two, three.
ある晴れた日のこと
One sunny day,
森のくまさんに出会った
I met a bear in the forest.
花咲く森の道
On a path in the flower-filled woods,
クマさんに出会った
I met a bear.
歩いてたらまた会うとき
When walking and meeting again,
笑いながらハミング
Humming with a smile,
嬉しさを集めよう
Let's gather up our happiness.
簡単なんだよそんなの
It's simple like that,
味わうよ
savoring it.
ドキドキするでしょ？
Makes your heart race, right?
でしょ？
Right?
これ若いころに覚えたからね
I learned this when I was young.
点をちょっと上げたいところだね
I'd like to raise the score a bit here.
その結果が
And the result...
4時受ケテンタイホ！
Arrested at 4:00!
船長逮捕！逮捕！
Captain, you're under arrest! Arrested!
ああ、確かになんか…やだ！
Ah, that's true... No way!
置いていって上がって逮捕でーす！
Left behind, going up, and arrested!
助けてください皆さん！
Help me, everyone!
ちなみに合わせられちゃいますね
By the way, you're getting matched up with it.
ずっとずっと踊れるようになるまでダンスレッスンを受けてもらいます。
You'll take dance lessons until you can dance on and on.
いいですか船長？
Is that okay, Captain?
アイドルたるものがダンスができないと、今後のライブにも立てないかもしれませんよ。
If an idol can't dance, you might not even stand on future stages.
わかりましたよ。分かった？
I understand. You got it?
踊り続けてね。
Keep dancing, okay?
じゃあ行くよ。
Then let's go.
じゃあ曲を流して踊った状態で皆さんにさようならしていきましょうか。
Shall we play music and say goodbye to everyone while dancing?
いいですか？じゃあ曲を流して船長踊ってて
Is that good? Play the music, Captain keep dancing,
祭りが最後の言葉するから。はい。
and Matsuri will say the final words. Okay.
じゃあミュージックスタート！
Then, music start!
皆さん本日は、#えむえもGOの配信にご覧いただきまして誠にありがとうございました！
Thank you for tuning into the #EmuEmoGO stream today!
船長はこの通りダンスレッスンを頑張っております！
The Captain is working hard on her dance lessons!
これからもアイドルになるために！
To become an idol from now on too!
船長のチャンネル登録もよろしくね、みんな！
Please subscribe to the Captain's channel too, everyone!
それじゃあ皆さん、また次回の配信でお会いしましょう！
Well then everyone, let's meet again in the next stream!
船長も一緒に…バイバーイ！
Captain, together... Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!